#### Contact

davidkeselman@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ davidkeselman (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Leadership Mentoring Career Development Coaching

## Languages

Hebrew Russian

#### Certifications

Mentor - Mentorship Program LEAN health Care Green Belt LEAN Health Care Yellow Belt Canadian Health Executive

#### **Publications**

Exploring the lived experience of male nurses in the pursuit of leadership roles: A phenomenological approach

Poverty and Health from the Health System Perspective

Ethical leadership

Maximizing The Scope of Practice of RPNs in The Community

Images of Nursing:"I'm just a nurse"

# Dr. David Keselman, RN, BScN, MN, DHA, STTI, CHE

Chief Executive Officer at Louis Brier Home & Hospital and Weinberg Residence

Yellowknife, Northwest Territories, Canada

## Summary

A health care executive with extensive experience in human resources management, finance and leadership. Proven successes in professional practice, strategic planning, operations, communication and education. Recognized for the ability to drive growth, build teams and communicate with diverse groups. A successful change-agent and visionary, able to support differences while maintaining healthy and positive work environments. Adapts to changing environments by establishing collegial and professional support networks, as well as encouraging open lines of communication with clear goals and objectives. Member of the Honor Society of Nursing (Sigma Theta Tau International) and the Canadian College of Health Leaders (CCHL). President of Men In Nursing Interest Group – RNAO

Specialties: Strong skills in leadership, operations, professional practice, quality and risk, negotiations, collaboration, team work, communication and conflict resolution. Strong skills in teaching, counselling and mentoring, quality improvement, change management and strategic planning.

## Experience

Louis Brier Home and Hospital Chief Executive Officer September 2016 - Present (3 years 11 months) Vancuver, British Columbia

Accreditation Canada Surveyor September 2010 - Present (9 years 11 months) Qualified surveyor, survey accredited health care organization on behalf of Accreditation Canada to ensure national accreditation standards are implemented through the delivery and provision of quality patient care.

Athabasca University
Sessional Instructor - Faculty of Health Sciences
January 2016 - Present (4 years 7 months)

Deliver online curriculum to students pursuing Masters of Nursing and or Masters of Health Science Graduate Programs.

Ryerson University
Continuing Education Instructor
September 2004 - Present (15 years 11 months)

Facilitate education and teaching of Diploma students through the continuing education department, in their persuit of a BscN degree. responsible for developing lesson plans and content. Utilizing adult education methods, online and OTN teaching methods.

Stanton Territorial Health Authority - Government of the North West Territories

VP Patient Services, Ambulatory Care, and Medical Affairs July 2011 - September 2016 (5 years 3 months) Yellow Knife

Reporting directly to the CEO, this position is responsible for providing strategic direction to multiple programs offered at the Stanton Territorial Health Authority (STHA). More specifically, responsible for the fiscal, human resources, practice and on-going operations of the nursing and physician services and programs, Ambulatory clinics and Ophthalmology services provided at the STHA. In addition, this position is responsible to lead the standardization and the streamlining of the Medical Travel program provided through the Government of the North West Territories (GNWT), to achieve a comprehensive territorial coverage, improved accessibility, utilization and efficiency. Acting CEO as required.

Dehcho Health and Social Services Authority A/CEO August 2013 - December 2013 (5 months) Fort Simpson

Rouge Valley Health System

Project Consultant and Nursing Administration Manager 2007 - November 2013 (6 years)

Provide after hours administrative and clinical support to staff, physicians, patients and families, facilitate patient flow, clinical practice, quality and safety.

Registered Nurses Association of Ontario President Men in Nursing 2007 - 2013 (6 years)

Men In Nursing is the official interest group of male nurses under the RNAO umbrella. Men in Nursing supports the practice of men in nursing by providing fore ground for networking, collaboration and awareness of the role of men within nursing. Men in Nursing's executive has been very successful in recruiting members to join the interest group, create and publish quarterly news letter, engage members through social networking and establish an active website. Recently, the group was successful in passing its first ever resolution at the RNAO's 2011 AGM.

York Central Hospital
Clinical Utilization and Patient Flow
2005 - September 2011 (6 years)

Provide after hours administrative and clinical support to staff, physicians, patients and families, facilitate patient flow, clinical practice, quality and safety. Communicate with extrenal and internal stakeholders (EMS and CCAC) to promote patient flow and optimal clinical utilization of resources.

VON Canada Executive Director July 2008 - 2011 (3 years)

GoodLife Fitness aqua instructor 2000 - 2011 (11 years)

Humber River Regional Hospital Program Director 2004 - 2008 (4 years)

University Health Network Nursing Administrative Coordinator 2000 - 2008 (8 years) William Osler Health Centre Patient Care Manager 2000 - 2004 (4 years)

Brmapton, Onatrio

# Education

Central Michigan University

Doctor of Health Administration, Health Administration · (2007 - 2012)

University of Toronto

Master of Nursing, Nursing · (1997 - 2001)

University of Toronto

BscN, Nursing · (1991 - 1995)